Dark Cloud is a science fiction, horror, mystery film directed by Jay Ness.
Following the aftermath of a horrific accident, a woman is voluntarily
subjected to artificial intelligence for rehabilitation.
Victoria, played by Brittany Benjamin.
Marla Harrison, played by Amanda Day.
Chloe Temple, played by Alexys Gabrielle.
Bruce Montgomery, played by Hugo Armstrong.
AIDA, played by Emily Atack.
Additional Voices (voice), played by Amanda Day.
Batman, a superhero created by Bob Kane and Bill Finger for comic books published by DC
Comics, has appeared in nearly every form of media, including film since the 1940s.
Columbia Pictures supervised the first film adaptations with Batman (1943) and Batman
and Robin (1949), deviating significantly from the source material.
20th Century Fox then released a theatrical spinoff of the American Broadcasting Company's (ABC)
live-action television series about the character in the 1960s, starring Adam West.
After several years in limbo, Warner Bros.
Pictures purchased the copyrights and developed a succession of Batman films in the late
twentieth century, two directed by Tim Burton and another pair by Joel Schumacher.
Michael Keaton portrays Batman in the Burton films, while Val Kilmer and George
Clooney feature as the titular hero in the Schumacher films.
Warner Bros.
spent the turn of the millennium in another protracted development period, leading to the production of a reboot trilogy
featuring Christian Bale as Batman: Batman Begins (2005), The Dark Knight (2008), and The Dark Knight Rises (2012).
The creation of the DC Extended Universe (DCEU), a media franchise
bound by a shared universe, spawned additional works.
Ben Affleck plays the character in the DCEU films, beginning with the Zack
Snyder-directed entry Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice (2016).
Affleck, Keaton, and Clooney's Batmen have also
appeared in crossover films within the DCEU.
The Batman (2022) and The Brave and the Bold will revamp the established continuity of the live-action
films with new incarnations of Batman portrayed by Robert Pattinson and another actor.
Joker (2019) features a depiction of the character as a civilian,
predating his transformation into a vigilante.
Numerous actors voice Batman in animated film.
The Batman films are generally successful and comprise one of the
highest-grossing franchises of all time, grossing over $6.8 billion globally.
Critical opinion of films vary substantially.
For example, The Dark Knight trilogy was critically acclaimed, whereas other films, such as
Batman & Robin (1997) and those of the DCEU, were not well reviewed in the media.
Occasionally, Batman films attract Academy Award
recognition for acting and technical achievement.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and thought_provoking.